{
    "Year": "2025",
    "Exam": "JEE Main 2025 January (22 Jan Shift 2)",
    "Questions": [
        {
            "Question_no": 1,
            "Question_text": "For a 3×3 matrix M, let trace(M) denote the sum of all the diagonal elements of M. Let A be a 3×3 matrix such that |A|=1/2 and trace(A)=3. If B=adj(adj(2A)), then the value of |B|+trace(B) equals:",
            "Options": [
                "56",
                "132",
                "174",
                "280"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "280",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 2,
            "Question_text": "In a group of 3 girls and 4 boys, there are two boys B₁ and B₂. The number of ways, in which these girls and boys can stand in a queue such that all the girls stand together, all the boys stand together, but B₁ and B₂ are not adjacent to each other, is:",
            "Options": [
                "96",
                "144",
                "120",
                "72"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "144",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 3,
            "Question_text": "Let α, β, γ and δ be the coefficients of x^7, x^5, x^3 and x respectively in the expansion of (x+\\sqrt{x^3-1})^5+(x-\\sqrt{x^3-1})^5, x>1. If u and v satisfy the equations αu+βv=18 and γu+δv=20 then u+v equals:",
            "Options": [
                "5",
                "3",
                "4",
                "8"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "5",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 4,
            "Question_text": "Let a line pass through two distinct points P(−2,−1,3) and Q, and be parallel to the vector 3\\hat{i}+2\\hat{j}+2\\hat{k}. If the distance of the point Q from the point R(1,3,3) is 5, then the square of the area of △PQR is equal to:",
            "Options": [
                "148",
                "136",
                "144",
                "140"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "136",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 5,
            "Question_text": "If A and B are two events such that P(A∩B)=0.1, and P(A|B) and P(B|A) are the roots of the equation 12x^2−7x+1=0, then the value of (P(A∪B))/(P(A∩B)) is:",
            "Options": [
                "4/3",
                "7/4",
                "5/3",
                "9/4"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "9/4",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 6,
            "Question_text": "If ∫ e^x\\left( \\frac{x\\sin^{-1}x}{\\sqrt{1-x^2}}+\\frac{\\sin^{-1}x}{(1-x^2)^{3/2}}+\\frac{x^2}{1-x^2}\\right)dx=g(x)+C, where C is the constant of integration, then g(1/2) equals:",
            "Options": [
                "(\\pi/4)\\sqrt{e/3}",
                "(\\pi/6)\\sqrt{e/3}",
                "(\\pi/4)\\sqrt{e/2}",
                "(\\pi/6)\\sqrt{e/2}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "(\\pi/6)\\sqrt{e/3}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 7,
            "Question_text": "The area of the region enclosed by the curves y=x^2−4x+4 and y^2=16−8x is:",
            "Options": [
                "8/3",
                "4/3",
                "8",
                "5"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "8/3",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 8,
            "Question_text": "Let f(x)=\\int_0^{x^2}\\frac{t^2−8t+15}{e^t}dt, x\\in \\mathbb{R}. Then the numbers of local maximum and local minimum points of f, respectively, are:",
            "Options": [
                "2 and 3",
                "2 and 2",
                "3 and 2",
                "1 and 3"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "2 and 3",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 9,
            "Question_text": "Let P(4,4\\sqrt{3}) be a point on the parabola y^2=4ax and PQ be a focal chord of the parabola. If M and N are the foot of perpendiculars drawn from P and Q respectively on the directrix of the parabola, then the area of the quadrilateral PQMN is equal to:",
            "Options": [
                "17\\sqrt{3}",
                "\\frac{263\\sqrt{3}}{8}",
                "\\frac{34\\sqrt{3}}{3}",
                "\\frac{343\\sqrt{3}}{8}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "\\frac{343\\sqrt{3}}{8}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 10,
            "Question_text": "Let \\vec{a} and \\vec{b} be two unit vectors such that the angle between them is \\pi/3. If \\lambda\\vec{a}+2\\vec{b} and 3\\vec{a}-\\lambda\\vec{b} are perpendicular to each other, then the number of values of \\lambda in [−1,3] is:",
            "Options": [
                "2",
                "1",
                "0",
                "3"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "0",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 11,
            "Question_text": "If \\lim_{x\\to\\infty}\\left(\\left(\\frac{1-e}{e}\\right)\\left(\\frac{1}{e}-\\frac{x}{1+x}\\right)\\right)^x=\\alpha, then the value of \\frac{\\log_e\\alpha}{1+\\log_e\\alpha} equals:",
            "Options": [
                "e^{-1}",
                "e^2",
                "e^{-2}",
                "e"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "e",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 12,
            "Question_text": "Let A=\\{1,2,3,4\\} and B=\\{1,4,9,16\\}. Then the number of many-one functions f:A\\to B such that 1\\in f(A) is equal to:",
            "Options": [
                "151",
                "139",
                "163",
                "127"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "151",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 13,
            "Question_text": "Suppose that the number of terms in an A.P. is 2k, k\\in \\mathbb{N}. If the sum of all odd terms of the A.P. is 40, the sum of all even terms is 55 and the last term of the A.P. exceeds the first term by 27, then k is equal to:",
            "Options": [
                "6",
                "5",
                "8",
                "4"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "5",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 14,
            "Question_text": "The perpendicular distance, of the line \\frac{x-1}{2}=\\frac{y+2}{-1}=\\frac{z+3}{2} from the point P(2,−10,1), is:",
            "Options": [
                "6",
                "5\\sqrt{2}",
                "4\\sqrt{3}",
                "3\\sqrt{5}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "3\\sqrt{5}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 15,
            "Question_text": "If the system of linear equations: x+y+2z=6; 2x+3y+az=a+1; −x−3y+bz=2b where a,b\\in \\mathbb{R}, has infinitely many solutions, then 7a+3b is equal to:",
            "Options": [
                "16",
                "12",
                "22",
                "9"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "16",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 16,
            "Question_text": "If x=f(y) is the solution of the differential equation (1+y^2)+\\left(x−2e^{\\tan^{-1}y}\\right)\\frac{dy}{dx}=0, y\\in\\left(−\\frac{\\pi}{2},\\frac{\\pi}{2}\\right) with f(0)=1, then f\\left(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}\\right) is equal to:",
            "Options": [
                "e^{\\pi/12}",
                "e^{\\pi/4}",
                "e^{\\pi/3}",
                "e^{\\pi/6}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "e^{\\pi/6}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 17,
            "Question_text": "Let \\alpha_\\theta and \\beta_\\theta be the distinct roots of 2x^2+(\\cos\\theta)x−1=0, \\theta\\in(0,2\\pi). If m and M are the minimum and the maximum values of \\alpha_\\theta^4+\\beta_\\theta^4, then 16(M+m) equals:",
            "Options": [
                "24",
                "25",
                "17",
                "27"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "25",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 18,
            "Question_text": "The sum of all values of \\theta\\in[0,2\\pi] satisfying 2\\sin^2\\theta=\\cos 2\\theta and 2\\cos^2\\theta=3\\sin\\theta is",
            "Options": [
                "4\\pi",
                "5\\pi/6",
                "\\pi",
                "\\pi/2"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "\\pi",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 19,
            "Question_text": "Let the curve z(1+i)+\\bar{z}(1−i)=4, z\\in\\mathbb{C}, divide the region |z−3|\\le 1 into two parts of areas \\alpha and \\beta. Then |\\alpha−\\beta| equals:",
            "Options": [
                "1+\\pi/2",
                "1+\\pi/3",
                "1+\\pi/6",
                "1+\\pi/4"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "1+\\pi/2",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 20,
            "Question_text": "Let E: x^2/a^2+y^2/b^2=1, a>b and H: x^2/A^2−y^2/B^2=1. Let the distance between the foci of E and the foci of H be 2\\sqrt{3}. If a−A=2, and the ratio of the eccentricities of E and H is 1/3, then the sum of the lengths of their latus rectums is equal to:",
            "Options": [
                "10",
                "9",
                "8",
                "7"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "8",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 21,
            "Question_text": "If \\sum_{r=1}^{30} \\frac{r^2 \\binom{30}{r}^2}{\\binom{30}{r-1}}=\\alpha\\times 2^{29}, then \\alpha is equal to ______",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "465",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 22,
            "Question_text": "Let A=\\{1,2,3\\}. The number of relations on A, containing (1,2) and (2,3), which are reflexive and transitive but not symmetric, is ______",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "3",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 23,
            "Question_text": "Let A(6,8), B(10\\cos\\alpha, −10\\sin\\alpha) and C(−10\\sin\\alpha, 10\\cos\\alpha), be the vertices of a triangle. If L(a,9) and G(h,k) be its orthocenter and centroid respectively, then (5a−3h+6k+100\\sin 2\\alpha) is equal to ______",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "145",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 24,
            "Question_text": "Let y=f(x) be the solution of the differential equation \\frac{dy}{dx}+\\frac{xy}{x^2−1}=\\frac{x^6+4x}{\\sqrt{1−x^2}}, −1<x<1 such that f(0)=0. If 6\\int_{-1/2}^{1/2} f(x)dx=2\\pi−\\alpha then \\alpha^2 is equal to ______ .",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "27",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 25,
            "Question_text": "Let the distance between two parallel lines be 5 units and a point P lie between the lines at a unit distance from one of them. An equilateral triangle PQR is formed such that Q lies on one of the parallel lines, while R lies on the other. Then (QR)^2 is equal to ______ .",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Mathematics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "28",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 26,
            "Question_text": "Logic circuit diagram with inputs A and B, containing NOT gates and AND gates, with output Y through gate G. Truth table: (A,B;Y): (0,0;1), (0,1;1), (1,0;0), (1,1;1). To obtain the given truth table, following logic gate should be placed at G:",
            "Options": [
                "OR Gate",
                "AND Gate",
                "NOR Gate",
                "NAND Gate"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_1"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "NOR Gate",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 27,
            "Question_text": "A small rigid spherical ball of mass M is dropped in a long vertical tube containing glycerine. The velocity of the ball becomes constant after some time. If the density of glycerine is half of the density of the ball, then the viscous force acting on the ball will be (consider g as acceleration due to gravity)",
            "Options": [
                "2Mg",
                "Mg",
                "(3/2)Mg",
                "Mg/2"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Mg/2",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 28,
            "Question_text": "The torque due to the force 2\\hat{i}+\\hat{j}+2\\hat{k} about the origin, acting on a particle whose position vector is \\hat{i}+\\hat{j}+\\hat{k}, would be",
            "Options": [
                "\\hat{i}−\\hat{k}",
                "\\hat{i}+\\hat{k}",
                "\\hat{j}+\\hat{k}",
                "\\hat{i}−\\hat{j}+\\hat{k}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "\\hat{i}−\\hat{k}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 29,
            "Question_text": "A symmetric thin biconvex lens is cut into four equal parts by two planes AB and CD as shown. If the power of original lens is 4 D then the power of a part of the divided lens is",
            "Options": [
                "1 D",
                "8 D",
                "2 D",
                "4 D"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_2"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "2 D",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 30,
            "Question_text": "For a short dipole placed at origin O, the dipole moment P is along x-axis. If the electric potential and electric field at A are V₀ and E₀, respectively, then the correct combination of the electric potential and electric field, respectively, at point B on the y-axis is given by",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_3"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "(2)",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 31,
            "Question_text": "A transparent film of refractive index 2.0 is coated on a glass slab of refractive index 1.45. What is the minimum thickness of transparent film to be coated for the maximum transmission of Green light of wavelength 550 nm. [Assume that the light is incident nearly perpendicular to the glass surface.]",
            "Options": [
                "137.5 nm",
                "275 nm",
                "94.8 nm",
                "68.7 nm"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "137.5 nm",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 32,
            "Question_text": "Given are statements for certain thermodynamic variables, (A) Internal energy, volume (V) and mass (M) are extensive variables. (B) Pressure (P), temperature (T) and density (\\rho) are intensive variables. (C) Volume (V), temperature (T) and density (\\rho) are intensive variables. (D) Mass (M), temperature (T) and internal energy are extensive variables. Choose the correct answer:",
            "Options": [
                "(B) and (C) Only",
                "(C) and (D) Only",
                "(D) and (A) Only",
                "(A) and (B) Only"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "(A) and (B) Only",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 33,
            "Question_text": "An electron projected perpendicular to a uniform magnetic field B moves in a circle. If Bohr's quantization is applicable, then the radius of the electronic orbit in the first excited state is:",
            "Options": [
                "\\sqrt{\\frac{h}{\\pi eB}}",
                "\\sqrt{\\frac{2h}{\\pi eB}}",
                "\\sqrt{\\frac{h}{2\\pi eB}}",
                "\\sqrt{\\frac{4h}{\\pi eB}}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "\\sqrt{\\frac{h}{\\pi eB}}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 34,
            "Question_text": "Assertion (A): In Young's double slit experiment, the fringes produced by red light are closer as compared to those produced by blue light. Reason (R): The fringe width is directly proportional to the wavelength of light. Choose the correct answer:",
            "Options": [
                "Both (A) and (R) are true but (R) is NOT the correct explanation of (A)",
                "(A) is true but (R) is false",
                "Both (A) and (R) are true and (R) is the correct explanation of (A)",
                "(A) is false but (R) is true"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "(A) is false but (R) is true",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 35,
            "Question_text": "A rectangular metallic loop is moving out of a uniform magnetic field region to a field free region with a constant speed. When the loop is partially inside the magnetic field, the plot of magnitude of induced emf (\\varepsilon) with time (t) is given by",
            "Options": [
                "Linear increase with t",
                "Exponential decay with t",
                "Exponential growth with t",
                "Step: constant then drops to zero"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_4a", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_4b", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_4c", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_4d"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Step: constant then drops to zero",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 36,
            "Question_text": "A ball of mass 100 g is projected with velocity 20 m/s at 60° with horizontal. The decrease in kinetic energy of the ball during the motion from point of projection to highest point is",
            "Options": [
                "5 J",
                "15 J",
                "20 J",
                "zero"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "15 J",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 37,
            "Question_text": "A body of mass 100 g is moving in circular path of radius 2 m on vertical plane. The velocity of the body at point A (lowest) is 10 m/s. The ratio of its kinetic energies at point B (30° from vertical through A) and C (horizontal level with center) is: (g=10 m/s^2)",
            "Options": [
                "(2+\\sqrt{2})/3",
                "(2+\\sqrt{3})/3",
                "(3+\\sqrt{3})/2",
                "(3-\\sqrt{2})/2"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_5"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "(3+\\sqrt{3})/2",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 38,
            "Question_text": "Assertion (A): A simple pendulum is taken to a planet of mass and radius, 4 times and 2 times, respectively, than the Earth. The time period of the pendulum remains same on earth and the planet. Reason (R): The mass of the pendulum remains unchanged at Earth and the other planet. Choose the correct answer:",
            "Options": [
                "(A) is false but (R) is true",
                "(A) is true but (R) is false",
                "Both (A) and (R) are true and (R) is the correct explanation of (A)",
                "Both (A) and (R) are true but (R) is NOT the correct explanation of (A)"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Both (A) and (R) are true but (R) is NOT the correct explanation of (A)",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 39,
            "Question_text": "A series LCR circuit is connected to an alternating source of emf E. The current amplitude at resonant frequency is I₀. If the value of resistance R becomes twice of its initial value then amplitude of current at resonance will be",
            "Options": [
                "2I₀",
                "I₀",
                "I₀/2",
                "I₀/\\sqrt{2}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "I₀/2",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 40,
            "Question_text": "Which one of the following is the correct dimensional formula for the capacitance in F? (M,L,T,C stand for mass, length, time, charge)",
            "Options": [
                "[C^2 M^{−1} L^{−2} T^{2}]",
                "[C^2 M^{−2} L^{2} T^{2}]",
                "[C M^{−2} L^{−2} T^{−2}]",
                "[C M^{−1} L^{−2} T^{2}]"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "[C^2 M^{−1} L^{−2} T^{2}]",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 41,
            "Question_text": "A tube of length L has radius at point (1) =2 cm and at point (2)=1 cm. If the velocity of water entering at (1) is 2 m/s, then velocity of water leaving at (2) will be",
            "Options": [
                "4 m/s",
                "2 m/s",
                "6 m/s",
                "8 m/s"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_6"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "8 m/s",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 42,
            "Question_text": "A light source of wavelength \\lambda illuminates a metal surface and electrons are ejected with maximum kinetic energy of 2 eV. If the same surface is illuminated by a light source of wavelength \\lambda/2, then the maximum kinetic energy of ejected electrons will be (The work function of metal is 1 eV)",
            "Options": [
                "3 eV",
                "2 eV",
                "6 eV",
                "5 eV"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "5 eV",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 43,
            "Question_text": "The maximum percentage error in the measurement of density of a wire is [Given, mass=(0.60±0.003) g, radius=(0.50±0.01) cm, length=(10.00±0.05) cm]",
            "Options": [
                "8",
                "5",
                "4",
                "7"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "5",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 44,
            "Question_text": "For a diatomic gas, if \\gamma_1=(C_p/C_v) for rigid molecules and \\gamma_2=(C_p/C_v) for another diatomic molecules but also having vibrational modes. Which option is correct?",
            "Options": [
                "\\gamma_2=\\gamma_1",
                "2\\gamma_2=\\gamma_1",
                "\\gamma_2<\\gamma_1",
                "\\gamma_2>\\gamma_1"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "\\gamma_2<\\gamma_1",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 45,
            "Question_text": "A force \\vec{F}=2\\hat{i}+b\\hat{j}+\\hat{k} is applied on a particle and it undergoes a displacement \\hat{i}−2\\hat{j}−\\hat{k}. What will be the value of b, if work done on the particle is zero.",
            "Options": [
                "0",
                "1/2",
                "2",
                "1/3"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "1/2",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 46,
            "Question_text": "A proton is moving undeflected in a region of crossed electric and magnetic fields at a constant speed of 2×10^5 m s^{−1}. When the electric field is switched off, the proton moves along a circular path of radius 2 cm. The magnitude of electric field is x×10^4 N/C. The value of x is _______. (m_p=1.6×10^{−27} kg)",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "2",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 47,
            "Question_text": "The net current flowing in the given circuit is ______ A. (Mixed network with resistors and a capacitor; source 2 V)",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_7"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "1",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 48,
            "Question_text": "A parallel plate capacitor of area A=16 cm^2 and separation 10 cm is charged by a DC current. Consider a hypothetical plane surface of area A_0=3.2 cm^2 inside the capacitor and parallel to the plates. At an instant, the current through the circuit is 6 A. At the same instant the displacement current through A_0 is ______ mA.",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "1200",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 49,
            "Question_text": "A tube of length 1 m is filled completely with an ideal liquid of mass 2M, and closed at both ends. The tube is rotated uniformly in horizontal plane about one of its ends. If the force exerted by the liquid at the other end is F then angular velocity of the tube is \\sqrt{\\frac{F}{\\alpha M}} in SI unit. The value of \\alpha is ______.",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "1",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 50,
            "Question_text": "Two long parallel wires X and Y, separated by a distance of 6 cm, carry currents of 5 A and 4 A, respectively, in opposite directions. Magnitude of the resultant magnetic field at point P at a distance of 4 cm from wire Y is x×10^{−5} T. The value of x is ________. (\\mu_0=4\\pi×10^{−7} SI units)",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_8"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Physics",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "1",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 51,
            "Question_text": "Statement (I): Nitrogen, sulphur, halogen and phosphorus present in an organic compound are detected by Lassaigne's Test. Statement (II): The elements present in the compound are converted from covalent form into ionic form by fusing the compound with Magnesium in Lassaigne's test. Choose the correct answer:",
            "Options": [
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 52,
            "Question_text": "Density of 3 M NaCl solution is 1.25 g/mL. The molality of the solution is:",
            "Options": [
                "1.79 m",
                "2.79 m",
                "2 m",
                "3 m"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "2.79 m",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 53,
            "Question_text": "The correct order of the following complexes in terms of their crystal field stabilization energies is: (1) [Co(NH3)4]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(en)3]^{3+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} (2) [Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} < [Co(NH3)4]^{2+} < [Co(en)3]^{3+} (3) [Co(en)3]^{3+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)4]^{2+} (4) [Co(NH3)4]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} < [Co(en)3]^{3+}",
            "Options": [
                "[Co(NH3)4]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(en)3]^{3+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+}",
                "[Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} < [Co(NH3)4]^{2+} < [Co(en)3]^{3+}",
                "[Co(en)3]^{3+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)4]^{2+}",
                "[Co(NH3)4]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} < [Co(en)3]^{3+}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "[Co(NH3)4]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{2+} < [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} < [Co(en)3]^{3+}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 54,
            "Question_text": "Statement (I): Corrosion is an electrochemical phenomenon in which pure metal acts as an anode and impure metal as a cathode. Statement (II): The rate of corrosion is more in alkaline medium than in acidic medium. Choose the correct answer:",
            "Options": [
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 55,
            "Question_text": "A reaction profile: Reactant at lower energy than product; activated complex at top. Marked energies E₁ (from reactant to peak) and E₂ (from product to peak). Consider the figure and choose the correct option:",
            "Options": [
                "Activation energy of both forward and backward reaction is E₁+E₂ and reactant is more stable than product.",
                "Activation energy of forward reaction is E₁+E₂ and product is less stable than reactant.",
                "Activation energy of backward reaction is E₁ and product is more stable than reactant.",
                "Activation energy of forward reaction is E₁+E₂ and product is more stable than reactant."
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_9"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Activation energy of forward reaction is E₁+E₂ and product is less stable than reactant.",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 56,
            "Question_text": "RBr \\xrightarrow{(i)\\ Mg,\\ dry\\ ether\\ \\ (ii)\\ H_2O} 2\\text{-Methylbutane}. The maximum number of RBr producing 2-methylbutane by above sequence of reactions is (consider the structural isomers only)",
            "Options": [
                "5",
                "4",
                "3",
                "1"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_10"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "4",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 57,
            "Question_text": "The species which does not undergo disproportionation reaction is:",
            "Options": [
                "ClO3^{−}",
                "ClO^{−}",
                "ClO2^{−}",
                "ClO4^{−}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "ClO4^{−}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 58,
            "Question_text": "The molar solubility (s) of zirconium phosphate (Zr^{4+})_3(PO4^{3−})_4 is given by relation:",
            "Options": [
                "\\left(\\frac{K_{sp}}{9612}\\right)^{1/7}",
                "\\left(\\frac{K_{sp}}{6912}\\right)^{1/7}",
                "\\left(\\frac{K_{sp}}{8435}\\right)^{1/7}",
                "\\left(\\frac{K_{sp}}{5348}\\right)^{1/6}"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "\\left(\\frac{K_{sp}}{6912}\\right)^{1/7}",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 59,
            "Question_text": "Identify the homoleptic complex(es) that is/are low spin. (A) [Fe(CN)5NO]^{2−} (B) [CoF6]^{3−} (C) [Fe(CN)6]^{4−} (D) [Co(NH3)6]^{3+} (E) [Cr(H2O)6]^{2+} Choose the correct answer:",
            "Options": [
                "(C) only",
                "(C) and (D) only",
                "(A) and (C) only",
                "(B) and (E) only"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "(C) and (D) only",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 60,
            "Question_text": "Match List-I with List-II: (A) (\\partial G/\\partial T)_p ; (B) (\\partial H/\\partial T)_p ; (C) (\\partial G/\\partial P)_T ; (D) (\\partial U/\\partial T)_V with (I) C_p, (II) −S, (III) C_v, (IV) V",
            "Options": [
                "(A)-(II), (B)-(I), (C)-(III), (D)-(IV)",
                "(A)-(I), (B)-(II), (C)-(IV), (D)-(III)",
                "(A)-(II), (B)-(I), (C)-(IV), (D)-(III)",
                "(A)-(II), (B)-(III), (C)-(I), (D)-(IV)"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_11"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "(A)-(II), (B)-(I), (C)-(IV), (D)-(III)",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 61,
            "Question_text": "Identify the number of structure/s from the following which can be correlated to D-glyceraldehyde.",
            "Options": [
                "four",
                "one",
                "two",
                "three"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_11a", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_11b", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_11c", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_11d"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "three",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 62,
            "Question_text": "Statement (I): A spectral line will be observed for a 2p_x \\to 2p_y transition. Statement (II): 2p_x and 2p_y are degenerate orbitals. Choose the correct answer:",
            "Options": [
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 63,
            "Question_text": "Statement (I): An element in the extreme left of the periodic table forms acidic oxides. Statement (II): Acid is formed during the reaction between water and oxide of a reactive element present in the extreme right of the periodic table. Choose the correct answer:",
            "Options": [
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 64,
            "Question_text": "Toluene (excess) undergoes: (i) CrO2Cl2, CS2 → Filter → Residue (A); (ii) H3O+; (iii) NaHSO3. Residue (A)+dil HCl → Compound (B). Structure of residue (A) and compound (B) formed respectively is:",
            "Options": [
                "Residue(A): benzene–CHO | Compound(B): benzene–COONa",
                "Residue(A): benzene–HC(=O) | Compound(B): benzene–C(=O)–OH",
                "Residue(A): benzene–CH(OCrOHCl2)2 | Compound(B): benzene–HC=O",
                "Residue(A): benzene–H–C(OH) and –SO3Na | Compound(B): benzene–HC=O"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_13a", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_13b", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_13c", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_13d", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_13e"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Residue(A): benzene–H–C(OH) and –SO3Na | Compound(B): benzene–HC=O",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 65,
            "Question_text": "The alkane from below having two secondary hydrogens is:",
            "Options": [
                "4-Ethyl-3,4-dimethyloctane",
                "2,2,3,3-Tetramethylpentane",
                "2,2,4,5-Tetramethylheptane",
                "2,2,4,4-Tetramethylhexane"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "2,2,3,3-Tetramethylpentane",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 66,
            "Question_text": "When sec-butylcyclohexane reacts with bromine in the presence of sunlight, the major product is:",
            "Options": [
                "Ring Br at secondary carbon attached to sec-butyl",
                "Ring bromination (equatorial)",
                "Br at tertiary position on sec-butyl group",
                "Br at secondary position on the sec-butyl chain"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_14a", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_14b", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_14c", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_14d"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "Br at tertiary position on sec-butyl group",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 67,
            "Question_text": "The most stable carbocation from the following is:",
            "Options": [
                "Benzyl cation (unsubstituted)",
                "p-OMe substituted benzyl cation (variant 1)",
                "p-MeO substituted benzyl cation",
                "p-CH3 substituted benzyl cation"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_15a", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_15b", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_15c", "https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_15d"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "p-MeO substituted benzyl cation",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 68,
            "Question_text": "Match the Compounds with Catalyst/Reagents for reduction into corresponding amines. (A) R–C(=O)–NH2; (B) Nitrobenzene; (C) R–C≡N; (D) Isoquinoline-1,3-dione (N–R). Reagents: (I) NaOH(aq); (II) H2/Ni; (III) LiAlH4, H2O; (IV) Sn,HCl",
            "Options": [
                "(A)-(II), (B)-(I), (C)-(III), (D)-(IV)",
                "(A)-(III), (B)-(II), (C)-(IV), (D)-(I)",
                "(A)-(II), (B)-(IV), (C)-(III), (D)-(I)",
                "(A)-(III), (B)-(IV), (C)-(II), (D)-(I)"
            ],
            "Diagram": ["https://fsphediyvqedjtvqkqap.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/JEE_Question_images/jan22n_16"],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "(A)-(III), (B)-(IV), (C)-(II), (D)-(I)",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 69,
            "Question_text": "Arrange in increasing order of dipole moment: HBr, H2S, NF3, CHCl3",
            "Options": [
                "H2S < HBr < NF3 < CHCl3",
                "NF3 < HBr < H2S < CHCl3",
                "HBr < H2S < NF3 < CHCl3",
                "CHCl3 < NF3 < HBr < H2S"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "NF3 < HBr < H2S < CHCl3",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 70,
            "Question_text": "The maximum covalency of a non-metallic group 15 element 'E' with weakest E−E bond is:",
            "Options": [
                "4",
                "6",
                "3",
                "5"
            ],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "4",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 71,
            "Question_text": "The compound with molecular formula C6H6, which gives only one monobromo derivative and takes up four moles of hydrogen per mole for complete hydrogenation has ______ electrons.",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "8",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 72,
            "Question_text": "20 mL of 2 M NaOH solution is added to 400 mL of 0.5 M NaOH solution. The final concentration of the solution is ______ ×10^{−2} M. (Nearest integer)",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "57",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 73,
            "Question_text": "Given standard enthalpies: C2H6(g)+7/2 O2(g)→2CO2(g)+3H2O(l), ΔH°=−1550 kJ/mol; C(graphite)+O2(g)→CO2(g), ΔH°=−393.5; H2(g)+1/2 O2(g)→H2O(l), ΔH°=−286. The magnitude of ΔH°_f(C2H6,g) is ______ kJ mol^{−1} (Nearest integer).",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "95",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 74,
            "Question_text": "Niobium (Nb) and ruthenium (Ru) have “x” and “y” number of electrons in their respective 4d orbitals. The value of x+y is ______.",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "11",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        },
        {
            "Question_no": 75,
            "Question_text": "The complex of Ni^{2+} ion and dimethyl glyoxime contains ______ number of Hydrogen (H) atoms.",
            "Options": [],
            "Diagram_Code": [],
            "Subject": "Chemistry",
            "Chapter": "",
            "Topic": "",
            "Subtopic": "",
            "Answer": "14",
            "Solution": "",
            "Difficulty": 0
        }
    ]
}